Just one man can make a difference.
Mad Max 2 is a adventure, action, thriller film directed by George Miller.
Max Rockatansky returns as the heroic loner who drives the dusty roads of a
postapocalyptic Australian Outback in an unending search for gasoline.
Arrayed against him and the other scraggly defendants of a fuel-depot encampment are the bizarre warriors commanded by
the charismatic Lord Humungus, a violent leader whose scruples are as barren as the surrounding landscape.
Max Rockatansky, played by Mel Gibson.
The Gyro Captain, played by Bruce Spence.
Pappagallo, played by Michael Preston.
The Toadie, played by Max Phipps.
Wez, played by Vernon Wells.
The Humungus, played by Kjell Nilsson.
Mad Max 2 (released as The Road Warrior in the United States) is a 1981 Australian post-apocalyptic dystopian
action film directed by George Miller, who co-wrote it with Terry Hayes and Brian Hannant.
It is the sequel to Mad Max (1979) and the second
installment in the Mad Max franchise.
The film stars Mel Gibson reprising his role as "Mad Max" Rockatansky and follows a hardened man who
helps a community of settlers to defend themselves against a roving band of marauders.
Filming took place in locations around Broken Hill,
in the Outback of New South Wales.
Mad Max 2 was released in Australia on 24 December 1981 to widespread critical acclaim; praise was given to Gibson's performance, the musical score,
cinematography, action sequences and costume design, with its sparing use of dialogue in particular being unprecedented for an action film.
It was also a box office success, and the film's post-apocalyptic and punk
aesthetics helped popularise the genre in film and fiction writing.
At the 10th Saturn Awards, the film won Best International Film and was nominated for five more awards: Best Director, Best
Actor for Gibson, Best Supporting Actor for Bruce Spence, Best Writing, and Best Costumes for Norma Moriceau.
Mad Max 2 is widely hailed as both one of the greatest action films of all time and one of the greatest sequels ever
made, and fan clubs for the film and "road warrior"-themed activities continue into the 21st century.
The film was followed by Mad Max Beyond Thunderdome in 1985.
The film explores themes of mask, australia, chase, explosive, dystopia.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.